what's up everybody I'm Phil bman with
Barb ben.com and we have a recap of the
2023 Olympia a lot of new Champions a
lot of rematches from last year and
everything else you're going to want to
know but before we dive in if you want
to follow along with anything in the
bodybuilding space just go over to
Google type in Barb ben.com and all of
that information that you're going to
want to see will come up the 2023
Olympia in Orlando Florida kicked off
with the 212 Olympia of course we knew
that Shan clarito was going to come in
as the defending champion and likely be
in the final call out and that's exactly
what he was he had a new contender this
time around in Keon Pearson and it was
clear that it was down to those two guys
for the gold going into the final call
out in the finals on Friday night
Clarita seems to be in this pattern
where he wins one year loses the next
year and then potentially regains the
next year because Keon Pearson is your
new 212 Olympia Champion Sean Clarita
comes in second again Clarita wins it
loses it to Derrick Lansford Derrick
Lunsford advances up to the Mr Olympia
competition Clarita wins it again last
year in 2022 this year Kon Pearson steps
up as a new Contender and takes makes
the gold for himself so it'll be
interesting to see next year in 2024
both guys are qualified now as past
champions We will see this rematch again
next year assuming both men stay healthy
it was quite a close run but Pearson on
top moving over into the figure division
the figure division has been dominated
for the last six years by Sydney Gillan
she is the reigning defending figure
champion and no one has really been able
to contest her over that run we saw
jessicaa Padilla last year come in and
challenge her for the first time we
thought we were going to see a rematch
that's exactly what we did the final
call out consisted of those two Lola
Montes and cheris Richardson we thought
potentially maybe this was the year
possibly that Sydney Gillan gives up the
title but no it was not to be the judges
still favored Gillan and Gillan takes
down her seventh consecutive title what
a dynasty still continuing through 2023
shifting over into the women's physique
Olympia this was a battle everybody was
expecting between the reigning champion
Natalia kjo and former two-time Champion
Sarah vas we knew that those two were
going to meet again in the final call
out and that's exactly what happened
they were joined by Brook Walker and Zab
Benta but it was really down to vas and
kjo and vas with the larger frame her
Immaculate conditioning as always is
able to regain the title she's now your
three-time women's Olympia Champion kjo
comes in second don't settle on this
matchup they will return in 2024 most
likely and we will see another rematch
between these two it is tight at the top
in this division it is a Quality quality
division all the way around all of the
women in this field have Exquisite
conditioning incredible muscle
separation and we're going to see this
match up again in 2024 we are looking
forward to it heading over into the
fitness competition now this division is
a little bit different from the other
divisions and that there are two rounds
a physique round and a performance round
but they are not even the performance
round consists of 2third of each
athletes overall score so an athlete can
lose in the physique round but make it
up in the performance round and still be
Crown the overall all champion in this
field Missy Truscott the defending
Champion comes in disaster strikes an
injury happens during her performance
and she is out of the top five Oxana
Gina the former two-time Champion comes
back after six years from the top of the
fitness Division and she reclaims the
crown and the $50,000 prize grishina on
top she will be able to go into 2024 to
defend that title we wish Miss TR Scott
the best we hope to see her again in
2024 but until then Gish is the fitness
Olympia champ Champion for 2023 moving
over to the Miss Olympia division Andrea
Shaw dominant in this division 3 years
running she's coming in as the defending
Champion nobody is in her League except
for Angela yao yao came in as the runner
up in 2022 and we knew we were going to
see a matchup again as you see there's
been this recurring theme in 2023 of
rematches from 2022 that's what we saw
again in the 2023 Miss Olympia contest
Shaw versus y we knew that was going to
be the match up going into the final
call out that in fact was they were
joined by beretto and priami but it was
really down to Shaw and Yao going into
the judges scorecards overall and it was
given to Andrea Shaw winning her fourth
consecutive Miss Olympia continuing her
Dynasty we're going to see both of those
athletes are actually going to see Shaw
Yao and Berto have all qualified for the
20124 Miss Olympia so we are likely to
see again the Yao versus Shaw matchup
again next year but until then Shaw
remains a top the Miss Olympia division
moving into the Wellness division the
final division contested on Friday night
at the 2020 three Olympia we were going
to see a rematch once again of the
reigning defending Champion over the
last two years franela Matos and
Isabelle Nunes we knew that they were
going to be in the running in the final
call out along with the Incredible
strength of the rest of the field the
final call out in the finals included
Ray and Fogo Francy alamatos Isabelle
Nunes and Alisa
Alcantara it came down to the final two
Matos versus Nunes they were separated
by exactly one point on the judges
scorecards and it really could have gone
either way both athletes brought
impeccable physiques to the the finals
here at the Olympia and it came down to
a single point that separated it and
gave it to the reigning defending Franc
El Matos wins her third Olympia straight
she is the only Wellness Champion to
ever have happened in this division so
far even though the the division is
Young it's only in its third year but
Matos is the champion every time so far
only one point separated her and Nunes
so we're going to see this rematch again
in 2024 and if it's that close it really
could go either way we're seeing this
division really come up it's really
impressive to see the physiques that
these women bring but francey alamatos
continues to be on top in Wellness
Switching gears and moving over to
Saturday's competition we had the
wheelchair Olympia kick things off after
prejudging in the morning for classic
physique men's physique and bikini and
everybody knew going into the wheelchair
that heral King Kong Kelly the reigning
Champion for the past 5 years he's the
only Champion the wheelchair Olympia has
ever seen and it was clear that if
anybody was going to beat him they were
going to have to bring their best and
Kelly was going to have to maybe be off
the mark what we saw was a final call
out between the reigning champion and
Harold Kelly and Poland's Carol myoi now
myoi had incredible shoulders incredible
upper body his muscle separation was
clear he had ABS that were comparable to
Kelly's it was a tight tight race at the
top and crowned new Champion Carol maloi
is your 2023 wheelchair Olympia Champion
he's the first Champion other than Kelly
of this division since its Inception
congratulations to Carol mooki we're
going to see this match up likely again
in 2024 Kelly is qualified for the
wheelchair division for life and now myi
is a champion so he himself is also
qualified they will return in 2024 well
hopefully we'll see another tight match
up as we did here in 2023 but myoi your
new 2023 wheelchair Olympia Champion
whoa light change we're here at Saturday
night at the 2023 Olympia in Orlando
Florida and we have four more divisions
to let you know about the first one
men's physique Ryan Terry versus Brandon
Hendrickson in the finals you heard that
right Aaron Banks the defending Champion
he gets knocked down into the bronze
position we have a final two between
Ryan Terry and Brenan Hendrickson
Hendrickson is a three-time men's
physique Olympia Champion Ryan Terry was
looking for his first title ever in his
nine appearances and that is exactly
what goes down Ryan Terry achieves his
first men's physique Olympia title after
receiving feedback from the judges he
put in work a lot differently this year
and it paid off he had a full physique
and his first Olympia title is in the
books switching over to Classic physique
a fan favorite Chris Bumstead was coming
in as the four-time defending Champion
he was going to go against a stacked
lineup that included Roman quz ERS Kel
sinki Brion anley Terrence Ruffin Wesley
vissers and a whole bunch of other
athletes in this field that were going
to put the pressure on Bumstead however
Bumstead is the standard when it comes
to Classic physique and he was not about
to give up his title anytime soon his
conditioning was Flawless his muscles
were full his striations and muscle
separation was on point Chris Bumstead
scores his fifth consecutive classic
physique Olympia title and continues his
Dynasty on top of the division moving
over to the penultimate division at the
2023 Olympia the bikini division we had
a staggering four out of five previous
bikini Olympia champions in the top five
Alisa Pacini she scores fifth the only
non- Olympia Champion Laura Lee shapos
comes in fourth Ashley CER the
winningest bodybuilder in ifbb Pro
history scores third she is consistent
as ever and the final two came down of
the last two Olympia Champions defending
Champion Morin blanquisco versus the
2021 Champion Jennifer Dory and by the
narrowest of margins it is Jennifer Dory
who reclaims the crown Blan Kisco comes
in second this is going to be an
exciting Division come 2024 a lot of
bikini division winners are going to
return in 2024 and it will be just as
stacked then as it was now but until
then Jennifer Dory is your 2023 bikini
Olympia champion and finally the big
money event the main event of the 2023
Olympia the 2023 Mr Olympia finals it
came down to three everyone knew after
prejudging and the final comparisons it
was going to come down to Samson dauda
the 2023 Arnold Classic Champion Derek
Lunsford the 2022 Mr Olympia runner-up
and the defending Champion hadti chupan
it was as close as it could possibly be
would Duda size overtake the other two
for the title would lunsford's Exquisite
shots from the back be able to overcome
his conditioned and gigantic competition
or with hotti chup Pan's incredible
muscularity and striations and muscular
density be able to offset the other two
and defend the throne when all was said
and done Samson daa takes the bronze and
in a crazy turn of events Derek Lunsford
is your 2023 Mr Olympia Champion he is
the first ever two Division Olympia
Champion he won the 212 division back in
2021 and then moved up to the Mr Olympia
competition last year where in his debut
in the division he scored second place
to HTI chupan and now in only his second
Mr Olympia appearance he becomes the
18th Mr Olympia Champion so there you
have it that's the 2023 Mr Olympia it
was a Wild Weekend some defended their
titles some lost their titles some
reclaimed their titles after losing it
in previous years it was a stacked
roster all the way down across all 11
divisions if we're seeing anything the
weight cap changes that were given to
each division brought significant
improvements to most of the athletes
physiques and it was tight all the way
through from Friday in pre- drudging to
Saturday finals we had a stack
competition here in Orlando Florida
until next time I'm Phil bman for barb.
thank you for watching our coverage of
the 2023 Mr Olympia and we'll see you
next
[Music]
time